{
  "categories": [
    {
      "name": "Geography",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What is the capital city of Switzerland?",
          "answers": ["Geneva", "Zurich", "Bern", "Lausanne"],
          "correctAnswer": "Bern"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which two countries in South America do not have a border with Brazil?",
          "answers": [
            "Chile and Colombia",
            "Argentina and Peru",
            "Ecuador and Bolivia",
            "Uruguay and Suriname"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Ecuador and Bolivia"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which African country is the most populous?",
          "answers": ["Nigeria", "Egypt", "Ethiopia", "South Africa"],
          "correctAnswer": "Nigeria"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which river is the longest in Europe?",
          "answers": ["Danube", "Volga", "Rhine", "Dnieper"],
          "correctAnswer": "Volga"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which city is located at the highest elevation above sea level?",
          "answers": [
            "La Paz, Bolivia",
            "Quito, Ecuador",
            "Kathmandu, Nepal",
            "Addis Ababa, Ethiopia"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "La Paz, Bolivia"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which country is known as 'the Land of the Rising Sun'?",
          "answers": ["China", "Japan", "South Korea", "Thailand"],
          "correctAnswer": "Japan"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which city is the capital of Canada?",
          "answers": ["Ottawa", "Toronto", "Vancouver", "Montreal"],
          "correctAnswer": "Ottawa"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Great Barrier Reef, one of the world's natural wonders, is located off the coast of which country?",
          "answers": ["Australia", "Brazil", "Mexico", "Egypt"],
          "correctAnswer": "Australia"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which mountain range is located between France and Spain?",
          "answers": ["Alps", "Himalayas", "Pyrenees", "Andes"],
          "correctAnswer": "Pyrenees"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which country is the largest producer of oil in the world?",
          "answers": ["United States", "Saudi Arabia", "Russia", "Canada"],
          "correctAnswer": "United States"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the capital city of South Africa?",
          "answers": ["Cape Town", "Johannesburg", "Pretoria", "Durban"],
          "correctAnswer": "Pretoria"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which Nordic country is known as the 'Land of the Midnight Sun'?",
          "answers": ["Sweden", "Finland", "Norway", "Iceland"],
          "correctAnswer": "Norway"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which country is known as 'the Land of a Thousand Lakes'?",
          "answers": ["Sweden", "Finland", "Canada", "Russia"],
          "correctAnswer": "Finland"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which Norwegian city is often referred to as the 'Gateway to the Fjords'?",
          "answers": ["Bergen", "Trondheim", "Stavanger", "Tromsø"],
          "correctAnswer": "Bergen"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Åland Islands, an autonomous archipelago, belong to which Nordic country?",
          "answers": ["Sweden", "Norway", "Finland", "Denmark"],
          "correctAnswer": "Finland"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which African country is known for its population of mountain gorillas?",
          "answers": ["Uganda", "Kenya", "Tanzania", "Rwanda"],
          "correctAnswer": "Rwanda"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Serengeti National Park, known for its annual wildebeest migration, is located in which African country?",
          "answers": ["Kenya", "South Africa", "Tanzania", "Botswana"],
          "correctAnswer": "Tanzania"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Komodo National Park, home to the Komodo dragon, is located in which country?",
          "answers": ["Indonesia", "Malaysia", "Thailand", "Philippines"],
          "correctAnswer": "Indonesia"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Arctic region is known for its polar bears. Which country is the largest habitat for polar bears?",
          "answers": ["Canada", "Russia", "Norway", "Greenland"],
          "correctAnswer": "Canada"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the world's largest river by volume?",
          "answers": ["The Nile", "The Amazon", "The Congo", "The Yangtze"],
          "correctAnswer": "The Amazon"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "name": "History",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "When were the first Olympic games held?",
          "answers": ["772 BC", "1896 AD", "776 BC", "692 BC"],
          "correctAnswer": "776 BC"
        },
        {
          "question": "What was the capital city of the Byzantine Empire?",
          "answers": ["Rome", "Constantinople", "Pompeii", "Antioch"],
          "correctAnswer": "Constantinople"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "name": "Technology",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Who is often credited as the inventor of the World Wide Web?",
          "answers": [
            "Tim Cook",
            "Tim Berners-Lee",
            "Kary Mullis",
            "James D. Watson"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Tim Berners-Lee"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does the abbreviation 'URL' stand for in the context of the internet?",
          "answers": [
            "Universal Resource Locator",
            "Universal Routing Link",
            "Unified Resource Language",
            "Unique Routing Locator"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Universal Resource Locator"
        },
        {
          "question": "What was the first commercially successful video game console, released in the early 1970's?",
          "answers": [
            "Atari 2600",
            "Magnavox Odyssey",
            "Nintendo Entertainment System (NES)",
            "Sega Genesis"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Magnavox Odyssey"
        },
        {
          "question": "In 2003, the popular music-streaming service Spotify was launched in which European country?",
          "answers": ["United Kingdom", "Sweden", "Finland", "Germany"],
          "correctAnswer": "Sweden"
        },
        {
          "question": "In computing, what does the acronym 'RAM' stand for?",
          "answers": [
            "Random Access Memory",
            "Remote Access Module",
            "Redundant Array of Memory",
            "Rapid Application Mode"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Random Access Memory"
        },
        {
          "question": "In 2018, Sweden became the first country to introduce what type of road, which can charge electric vehicles as they drive?",
          "answers": [
            "Electric highways",
            "Solar roads",
            "Wireless charging roads",
            "Smart roads"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Electric highways"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which Swedish music streaming service was founded in 2006 and acquired by Spotify in 2014?",
          "answers": ["SoundCloud", "Pandora", "Tidal", "Rdio"],
          "correctAnswer": "Tidal"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the name of the first commercially successful video game, released in 1972?",
          "answers": ["Pong", "Super Mario Bros.", "Pac-Man", "Space Invaders"],
          "correctAnswer": "Pong"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which technology company developed the first graphical user interface (GUI)?",
          "answers": ["Apple", "Microsoft", "IBM", "Xerox"],
          "correctAnswer": "Xerox"
        },
        {
          "question": "What technology is commonly used to assist individuals with visual impairments to navigate their surroundings?",
          "answers": [
            "Virtual Reality (VR)",
            "Augmented Reality (AR)",
            "Voice Assistants",
            "Wearable Sensors"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Voice Assistants"
        },
        {
          "question": "In the field of fertility, what is the name of the process that involves combining an egg and sperm outside the body to facilitate conception?",
          "answers": [
            "In Vitro Fertilization (IVF)",
            "Artificial Insemination (AI)",
            "Surrogacy",
            "Gamete Intrafallopian Transfer (GIFT)"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "In Vitro Fertilization (IVF)"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the process of using sensors, robotics, and data analytics to optimize agricultural practices?",
          "answers": [
            "Precision farming",
            "Organic farming",
            "Hydroponics",
            "Aquaponics"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Precision farming"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which technology allows people with limited mobility to control electronic devices using their brain activity?",
          "answers": [
            "Virtual Reality (VR)",
            "Brain-Computer Interface (BCI)",
            "Assistive Robotics",
            "Prosthetics"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Brain-Computer Interface (BCI)"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which technology is used to track and monitor wildlife populations in their natural habitats?",
          "answers": [
            "Satellite tracking",
            "Drones",
            "DNA analysis",
            "Radio telemetry"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Radio telemetry"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the name of the technology that allows for the growth of plants in a soil-less environment using nutrient-rich water?",
          "answers": [
            "Aquaculture",
            "Hydroponics",
            "Aeroponics",
            "Vertical farming"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Hydroponics"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which technology is used to monitor and analyze the movement patterns of marine animals, such as whales and dolphins?",
          "answers": [
            "GPS tracking",
            "Acoustic tags",
            "Satellite imaging",
            "Sonar systems"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Acoustic tags"
        },
        {
          "question": "What technology is used to genetically modify crops to enhance traits such as pest resistance or increased yield?",
          "answers": [
            "Gene editing",
            "Selective breeding",
            "Tissue culture",
            "Genome sequencing"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Gene editing"
        },
        {
          "question": "What technology is used to identify and analyze patterns in large sets of data to gain insights and make informed decisions?",
          "answers": [
            "Artificial intelligence (AI)",
            "Machine learning",
            "Data mining",
            "Predictive analytics"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Data mining"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "name": "Science",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What does the mass number of an atom indicate?",
          "answers": [
            "The number of protons",
            "The number of neutrons",
            "The number of protons and neutrons",
            "The number of electrons"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "The number of protons and neutrons"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many bones are there in the human body?",
          "answers": ["216", "206", "208", "214"],
          "correctAnswer": "206"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "name": "Sports",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "What does the mass number of an atom indicate?",
          "answers": [
            "The number of protons",
            "The number of neutrons",
            "The number of protons and neutrons",
            "The number of electrons"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "The number of protons and neutrons"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many bones are there in the human body?",
          "answers": ["216", "206", "208", "214"],
          "correctAnswer": "206"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "name": "Music",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Which American singer-songwriter released the album 'Rumours' with their band in 1977?",
          "answers": [
            "Neil Young",
            "Joni Mitchell",
            "Stevie Nicks",
            "Fleetwood Mac"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Fleetwood Mac"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which female singer went solo from Clannad?",
          "answers": ["Sinead O'Conner", "Moya", "Enya", "Dolores O'Riordan"],
          "correctAnswer": "Enya"
        },
        {
          "question": "What kind of triangle did Barry Manilow sing about in 1981?",
          "answers": [
            "a love triangle",
            "the Bermuda triangle",
            "the golden triangle",
            "a triangular trade"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "the Bermuda triangle"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which Genesis drummer had three big hits in the 1980's?",
          "answers": [
            "John Silver",
            "Phil Collins",
            "John Mayhew",
            "Chris Stewart"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Phil Collins"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many Jacksons were there when they sang “I Want You Back”?",
          "answers": ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
          "correctAnswer": "5"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Eagles' reunion album, released in 1994, is titled:",
          "answers": [
            "Hotel California Revisited",
            "The Long Road",
            "Hell Freezes Over",
            "Eagles Forever"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Hell Freezes Over"
        },
        {
          "question": "What was the name of Frank Zappa's independent record label?",
          "answers": [
            "Zappa Records",
            "Barking Pumpkin Records",
            "Mothership Records",
            "Freak Out! Records"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Barking Pumpkin Records"
        },
        {
          "question": "What color was Prince's iconic custom-made guitar?",
          "answers": ["Purple", "Blue", "Green", "Multicolored"],
          "correctAnswer": "Purple"
        },
        {
          "question": "Hootie & the Blowfish took a hiatus in the early 2000's, during which Darius Rucker pursued a successful solo career in which genre?",
          "answers": ["Country", "Hip-hop", "Jazz", "Rock"],
          "correctAnswer": "Country"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which iconic singer originally recorded the song 'I Will Always Love You', later popularized by Whitney Houston?",
          "answers": [
            "Elvis Presley",
            "Reba McEntire",
            "Dolly Parton",
            "Aretha Franklin"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Dolly Parton"
        },
        {
          "question": "Who is the drummer and primary lyricist of Rush?",
          "answers": ["Alex Lifeson", "Neil Peart", "Geddy Lee", "John Rutsey"],
          "correctAnswer": "Neil Peart"
        },
        {
          "question": "What was the original name of the band Queen?",
          "answers": [
            "The Bohemians",
            "Smile",
            "Mercury Rising",
            "The Royalists"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Smile"
        },
        {
          "question": "What was the tragic event that occurred on October 20, 1977, involving Lynyrd Skynyrd?",
          "answers": [
            "Their tour bus crashed",
            "Their plane crashed",
            "They were banned from performing in certain states",
            "Their instruments were stolen"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Their tour bus crashed"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which keyboard instrument did Ray Manzarek play in The Doors?",
          "answers": ["Piano", "Organ", "Synthesizer", "Harpsichord"],
          "correctAnswer": "Organ"
        },
        {
          "question": "Bob Marley's iconic song 'No Woman, No Cry' was recorded live at which venue?",
          "answers": [
            "Madison Square Garden",
            "Royal Albert Hall",
            "Tuff Gong Studio",
            "Lyceum Theatre"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Lyceum Theatre"
        },
        {
          "question": "What was the title of ZZ Top's successful 1983 album that brought them mainstream popularity?",
          "answers": ["Eliminator", "Recycler", "Rhythmeen", "Afterburner"],
          "correctAnswer": "Eliminator"
        },
        {
          "question": "AC/DC's distinctive logo features what type of object?",
          "answers": ["Lightning bolt", "Skull", "Guitar", "Cannon"],
          "correctAnswer": "Lightning bolt"
        },
        {
          "question": "Iron Maiden's mascot Eddie has appeared on many of their album covers. In which album did Eddie take the form of a mummified pharaoh?",
          "answers": [
            "Seventh Son of a Seventh Son",
            "Fear of the Dark",
            "Powerslave",
            "Somewhere in Time"
          ],
          "correctAnswer": "Powerslave"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
